[music]
Everybody
hey every hey
everybody
hey hey hey hey hey hey hey hey hey hey
hey hey hey don't do going fast hey hey
hey
don't me hey Everybody [music]
let every me
every day. [music]
Hey.
[music]
Hey. Hey.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat.
Heat. [music]
[music]
Heat. Hey. Hey. Hey.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Got to feel you.
Now you're [music]
feeling
>> [music]
>> Hey,
hey, hey.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hey, hey, hey. [music] Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Good morning everyone. Thanks for
joining us. You're watching Drogram with
Ted R and John Kuryaku. Sitting in in
the John chair is editorial [laughter]
cartoonist for the Chicago Tribune,
Scott Stantis. Scott, thanks for joining
us.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> Thanks for filling in. John will be back
on Monday. We're here Monday through
Friday, 9:00 a.m. Eastern time. Uh
John's nothing uh nothing terrible. He's
attending a funeral, but it's uh for an
elderly relative. Um, you know, I always
think that it's funny when we think,
well, you know, it's not the tra not a
tragedy because they lived to be old,
but you know, you miss them more if they
lived to be old because you knew them
longer.
>> You think?
>> I mean, I'm just saying it's worth
considering that possibility unless you
got sick of them because you knew them
for so long and you're [laughter] like,
"Bye."
>> Well, that plus, you know, they dementia
and other things which you and I have
both dealt with. I mean that that it can
be actually a blessing when they
>> it can be I mean or at least a mercy
let's put it that way.
>> Um some people it's a blessing you know
not it's not always bad when people die.
Um okay so [laughter] that's dark. Uh
it's
Anyway um thanks everyone. Please like
follow and share the show. Um please
continue. Um so we did achieve our
thousands for Robbie Aid. Um thank you
everyone for getting us to $1,000. We do
that every month in order to keep our
producer who we, you know, as you guys
know very much we really need. Robbie
will be in the background and starting
about half an hour. He's got something
to do this morning. If you would like to
uh, you know, kick in and tip, it
doesn't hurt. Uh, he can use the money.
He's still, you know, this is his job
now. Goofundme.comfdprogrambie
or you just go to gofundme and search
for dprogram Robbie as one word. Um,
thanks for uh everything. Uh, okay. So,
lots going on. Um, we're going to go
over this report that came out of the UK
that's blaming uh President Putin of
Russia for that 2018 poisoning of a 44
year old British woman. Uh, we'll get
into the details there. Uh, also the New
York Times has a new report about how
the corruption in the Zilinsky
government and exactly how it works. Um,
and you know, it's not a big secret, but
the how is kind of somewhat interesting.
So, we'll get into that. Uh obviously
all eyes right now are focused on the
Pete Hegsth career death watch. Will he
survive the media the Friday afternoon
Sunday a Saturday morning traditional
media dump when resignations and firings
occur at times like this? If he's still
DoD chief by Sunday morning, I'd say
he's safe for the time.
>> D Ted,
>> that's right. That's right. Although
it's not formally that. So, I'm still
gonna call him the sec death whether he
likes it or not. Um, I mean, he might
drone me. That could happen, but you
know, like on the air, at least I'd get
ratings for once. Um, [laughter] so, and
new poll out, um, Trump's disapproval
rating is continuing to increase. Can
the Republicans save their asses? Uh,
lots of questions in the YouTube chat to
get through before we start these
things. And also, as if that wasn't
enough action-packed deprogramming for
you today, um there's breaking news. You
guys probably, if you have a phone,
you've already seen it. Netflix is uh
has just committed to purchase Warner
Brothers, the uh legendary film studio,
but they also have a bunch of other
properties, including Max, uh which HBO
Max, which was HBO, then it became Max,
now it's HBO Max. Sounds like I just
think of Maxipad every time I hear.
>> Yeah, me too. um $83 billion dollar. Um
obviously there are antirust
implications here. Um I know Scott you
have thoughts about that and
>> yeah and let me just say that I I I I
can't speak for John but I think I can
on this instance and say that if Netflix
wants to buy this podcast for [laughter]
half that amount
I have to believe that even socialist
Ted R
would have to say yes. Well, we do live
in a cap we do live in a capitalist
system. So, until the revolution comes,
as Jean Paul Sartra said, we must all
live with the system that we have. So,
yes, you you are correct. All right,
let's do some questions, then we'll get
to our first topic. And Scott, you can
think of what you want to talk about
first because there's the order is not
really that important. Okay, so Elliot
Cover T, thank you very much for this
question. With Ukraine appearing to be
on its last legs and Russia poised for
victory, have Western elites learned
anything about how to conduct prudent
foreign policy since 2022? This will be
a short answer. Scott,
>> I'm sorry, Ted and I have been talking
about this for years and the problem is,
you know, initially I was very much in
support of Ukraine uh because they were
invaded u and nobody likes to be
invaded. However, now that this this has
gone on, you can't keep calling
something a democracy if it doesn't
have, you know, democracy. So, in this
instance, the the report on the
corruption is no no surprise because
Zilinsky has shut down all opposition.
He shut down all elections. And when you
do that, well, you've opened the gates,
the floodgates for all sorts of
mischief. And I mean, this is Ted, you
cannot, of all people, Ted R cannot be
surprised.
>> No. Uh, no. No, and we'll be getting
into the Zalinski corruption story, but
I mean, you know, have have the have the
US policy makers learned anything? No,
clearly not. I mean, look at look at
what's going on now. We'll be talking
about the Venezuela situation, but um
you know, Venez the approach to
Venezuela makes the neocon attack on
Afghanistan and Iraq look positively
professional by comparison. I mean,
[laughter] they're not they're not even
bothering to message the American people
about it. and the the legal um you know
structures are as flimsy as a as a Jenga
game uh right before the very end right
I mean it's completely insane um so no
they haven't learned anything um another
question from Medorasian I'm sorry if I
mispronounced that I'm curious about
your perspectives on the Arab Spring
role did Obama and the CIA play and how
did Egypt fall in 2012 the Arab Spring
of course started in Tunisia um with the
overthrow of Ben Ali
Um the and of course uh the the fall of
uh Hosni Mubarak in um in Egypt was a
big part of it. Look the the CIA played
a huge role in the overthrow the Ben Ali
thing less so uh but in terms of Egypt
we you know the CIA the US called
Mubarak and said you've got to step down
and um and basically you know the Egypt
was a client state. I mean this by the
way I like this is one of my favorite
rants. I always say you can't have a
nonviolent revolution and the you know
terir square and the um the the
overthrow of Mubarak was largely a
peaceful affair. I mean not to say that
there was no violence or anything. In
fact I know a woman a reporter who was
there for Alazer in Ter Square and she
was raped in Terrar Square. Okay. So by
by gross guys um who were there. So it
you know it's not like there was no
violence but I mean it was not a
revolution right as you and I both know
it from history. And and what do you get
out of that? You end up with Alsisi who
is no completely the same as Mubar.
>> Yeah.
>> He's exactly
>> it comes out of the um you know the
dictator [laughter]
the dictator factory out of central Ohio
where they produce these guys. Hey audio
for some reason. I'm gonna I'm gonna
jump off and then jump back on. Okay.
>> Okay. Maybe you can use your phone.
Switch to your phone or whatever.
>> This technical glitch.
>> Okay, that's totally fine. Um Okay. So,
uh as Scott Stantis tries to uh get his
get back in, and I'll put him back in
right away. Um this happened yesterday
on the DMZ America podcast, so I have a
feeling that Scott needs to call his uh
tech people. But anyway, um thank you.
Thank you, Fuso, for the uh dollar
donation. Sloppy Russian spies, which
the the title of today's uh today's uh
broadcast. Sounds snotty. Yeah, it kind
of does. That was kind of like my that
was my duty. Scott, do you hear me now?
>> I do. And I apologize for
>> Great. Yeah, no worries. You know, these
things happen uh all the time,
unfortunately. Um comment that I think
is worth mentioning from Triple JXYZ.
The peasants are sent to the meat
grinder while the elite uh enjoy caviar
in a in a Swiss ski village courtesy of
US and EU taxpayers. Of course. Oh yeah,
that's always been the case. I mean, I'm
trying to think it was Oh, yeah. The
presidents of Mexico. I think there are
more ex-presidents and former presidents
of Mexico in Connecticut than there are
actually in Mexico.
And I think that's that's a fact. Um
they don't stick around. They get their
Luger and they move on. And so, yeah,
Zilinski is going to be in Switzerland,
didn't you say? There's um
>> he has several places. He has a Yeah.
Place in Lake Ko. Um and so he could he
could easily end up in Germany, Italy,
France. I have a feeling he'll end up in
France because it looks like Macron is
his best boy.
>> Okay. Well, there you go. [laughter]
It's And it's unfortunate because as I
say, initially he seemed to be a
righteous fighter against an invasion of
his country and that Okay. Did he
really?
>> He did. Yeah. Come on.
>> It's funny because I don't I don't
remember having that opinion and I don't
think I expressed
>> You did not. I did and most most people
did. Um because that was the optics. But
then, you know, as you pointed out, you
were one of the few ones who w who who
was because it was, you know, not not
kosher to say that he was that he
Zalinsky was somehow not a Democrat,
>> a grifter. Well, it turns out that uh
yeah, he that's exactly what he
>> What since when has anything bad ever h
happened from electing an actor as
president?
>> Oh, something some good things happen.
Let's be clear.
>> Well, in your opinion. [laughter]
Uh okay. But anyway, go ahead. I I I
apologize. I interrupted.
>> That's all right. I was just saying one
time we did it, we had the largest uh
economic expansion in the history of the
country.
>> So that's that that would be a good
thing.
>> Really? Bill Clinton wasn't an actor,
though. That was the biggest
>> Bill Clinton I think took got there's a
lot of momentum coming from the Reagan
Reagan
>> George HW Bush administration and the
1990 recession
>> that was such a shallow recession. God
you have one recession they hold it
against you forever. Well, it's it was
personal to me because I graduated in
1991 from Colombia and you know, you
know, that used to be a good school
before it was descertified uh by Trump.
It was and uh it's like you got out and
literally they canceled the jobs fair.
Not one single employer was Yeah. Not
one single employer. Well, and this is
what I mean this plays into other
events, recent events, uh when George HW
Bush in 1991 said that the the recession
was over.
>> And you don't do that. Don't tell the
American people
>> that they're doing. In fact, it's you
know, this is kind of like you you ever
see that French movie, Scott, called
Ridicule? If you haven't, you would love
it. It's a costume drama.
>> No.
>> Uh well worth seeing. Look it up. Um
basically, it's about a young um poor
aristocrat. those things did exist from
a swampy part of southern France who is
basically goes to Paris and hangs out at
the court in order to curry favor to try
to get royal funds so that they can you
know drain the swamps literally in his
district and get rid of malaria that's
afflicting his the peasants. So he go
and they tell him basically what he's
going to have to do to suck up and
become popular in the French court which
is and and and yeah and and basically
>> wait why did I bring this up? What did
you just say before that? Um, oh my god.
>> Well, about George HW Bush saying that
the recession was over.
>> Yes. And he said, and so one of the one
of the pieces of advice that the older
experienced aristocrat tells this young
man is never laugh at your own joke.
Always let other people praise you. And
I think that's really valuable.
>> Okay. Do you laugh at your own jokes?
Because I laugh at my own jokes. If I I
will admit that if if it's really a good
joke or in my in my opinion I I find
myself doing that and then I remember
the movie. Don't do that. Stop that. Um
all right, let's let's talk about the
another question here. Sherlock Holmes,
any update on the Lou Crown Jewels? I
feel like that is a downplayed story. Um
no. Uh basically there's been some
arrests. Uh the the the French are
investigating. The jewels have not been
recovered. That's a, you know, and by
the way, nor were they insured.
>> Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait. I'm sorry.
This is a piece of information I did not
know. They were not insured.
>> No, according to the Louver, which used
to be like Colombia, an institution that
had that was worth something. They
couldn't afford the insurance, the uh
the coverage. I guess it's like
Obamacare. The premiums were just too
high. So the uh they couldn't afford it
and they're like, "Ah, we'll be fine."
So
>> what's the worst that can happen?
[laughter]
>> Exactly. So yeah, so the jewels are MIA
still. The uh I would imagine that look,
the French police and the surite are are
not it's not unknown for them to torture
people in custody. So I would imagine
that uh the the thieves h are currently
like hanging from the ceiling uh and and
you know having a very un very bad day
and very bad night every day and being
like where are the jewels? Where are the
jewels?
Um
so uh but we will obviously keep you
posted uh when anything uh breaks on
that.
>> Story.
>> Uh yeah
>> amazing. I mean just to I mean and it's
not high-tech. It's not like it was like
they got a ladder. That was pretty much
it. It was a bunch. It sounds so far.
Although there's there now that the fact
that they can't find the jewels, but
doesn't it sound like it was just a
bunch of kids said, "Hey dude, we got a
ladder." [laughter] Yeah. Like I got the
ladder for the weekend. Let's go. Um
yeah, you know, it sounded like it was a
really wellexecuted thing until we
figured out it wasn't. Um I [laughter]
know.
>> Okay. Village Idiot TV, thanks for the
question. Disagrees with me. Perhaps the
civil rights in the movement in the
United States was a kind of nonviolent
revolution if only regionally also India
uh must maintain hope for non-violent
change. I maintain hope for the second
coming of Jesus Christ but it's not
going to happen. And uh and similarly
look the civil rights movement was not a
revolution is the replacement of one
class of elites by another. It involves
as mount it is not a dinner party. It is
the violent overthrow of one cast and
people do not you know one class of
elites does not give up that power
nonviolently ever and in terms of India
that's also not a revolution that's an
independent struggle and I'll save you
the trouble South Africa uh the struggle
against apartheid is uh that's an
emancipation movement also not a
revolution as proven by the fact that
the rich white Africaners who were rich
afric white Africconers before 1986 six
are still rich white counters today. If
a revolution had happened, that would
not be true today. But I do maintain I
maintain hope for the second coming of
Christ and for the second coming of
print media.
>> To be fair, um you know um the um
they're now they're soon to be um rich
white Americans because they're the only
ones apparently who [laughter] immigrate
here. Now
>> that's a good point. Thanks for that
correction, Scott. Um Philip Blair has a
political cartooning related question.
Sure. Didn't they try to tell us the
Arab Spring happened because a political
cartoonist made a 14minute video? What
was the political cartoon angle?
>> Oh, right. Oh gosh, I have a vague
memory of that. And do you do you
remember it, Ted? Because I'm trying.
>> I have a vague memory of it, too. Um
>> Um and it wasn't um it wasn't Farat in
Syria who was the cartoonist and um
Assad's goons picked him up and beat him
to within an inch of his life. Broke
both his hands. is pretty atrocious. Uh
but that's not what's what the trigger
was. The trigger was um
oh my gosh. And now I'm trying to
remember what was another scandal. Oh um
Hillary Clinton and the uh the video
that triggered the killings in um Libya.
Oh gosh.
Remember that Ted? The um
>> oh the am not the ambassador but the um
yeah the ambassador
>> Benghazi attack.
>> What's that? the Benghazi at the attack
on the Benghazi consulate. Yeah.
>> And that that was that was caused by a
video
>> that had like three views,
>> right? And also was and there was also
Yeah, I remember part of the blame was
uh not a video, right? But it was the um
Danish Muhammad cartoons,
>> right? Well, that's what that the video
was about. It showed them on YouTube. It
was a YouTube video that creepy.
>> Yeah. So, all right. So to refresh
people's memories, um there was a um a
Danish newspaper, a satirical magazine
that published um a series of cartoons
basically that were just like Muhammad
sucks cartoons. Um and they're they're
kind of if you see them now, you're
probably like, "Oh, I remember those."
Um one's famous one's got like one where
Muhammad's turban is a oldfashioned bomb
with the with the fuse sticking out. Um
and there's a bunch of others. Anyway,
those cartoons, it's hard to overstate
just how much [__] they caused around
the world as they were spread by rabble
rousers like basically radical Islamists
in Kbble and all over the world, Cairo.
They showed them. There were demonst
mass demonstrations all over the place.
Um, you know, I mean, there were
assassins dispatched to kill those
cartoons. There was a fatwa the cartoon.
One guy, I love this story. Um the he
was sitting in his uh his house in
Copenhagen and he was like he had like a
a Jodie Foster style safe room in his
house. I mean as all cartoonists do and
as Scott and I do guys don't remember
don't forget that. Um but he had tricked
out his house like a fortress in
preparation for this. And some murderer,
some al-Qaeda type dude, some ISIS type
dude show broke into his house with a
[__] you know, AR-15, probably an
AR-15, but an ARX-15 style gun, armed to
the teeth, grenades, the whole thing.
And the guy basically went to his safe
room, the cartoonist. [laughter] He was
like 65, like, and basically locked all
the doors, and he had speakers in there.
It was like a movie. And he's like,
"Hey, [__] Guess what? You're locked
in. I'm safe. the cops are on their way.
[__] you. And like started insulting the
prophet and like just going on and on
until the cops arrived [laughter] and
the guy's just sitting in there drinking
port and just like waiting for for the
whole thing to happen. I was just like,
you know, I don't appreciate the cartoon
and I'm not sure it was a good idea to
be to insult someone's religion
gratuitously.
But that said, I gotta hand it to that
cartoonist. That's some pretty balls out
action.
>> Yeah, I love that. We um we may or may
not have safe rooms if anyone's
listening who may want to do us harm.
I'm just want to be I want I want to be
really clear that you don't know that we
don't have a safe room.
>> Well, that's true. And I would
>> really clear.
>> Not to mention I also have an attack cat
>> and will the the the bloodshed there's
already been enough bloodshed due to
that cat and nobody needs to see
anymore. So, ISIS, I'm looking at you.
[__] off.
>> Well, we we just got a dog and I um he's
been leaving telltale signs that the
squirrel issue we were dealing with is
no longer an issue. Just saying. There's
a pile of fluff and bones around the
I've stumbled across in our backyard
now.
>> You know, things can things turn ugly
when animals do [__] All right. So,
let's What do you want to talk about
first? Um Novachuk Zalinski.
>> Zilinski is a great I mean, here's the
thing. about Zinsky. If you followed Ted
and I also do another podcast called DMZ
America and for years you and I have
been talking about this and as I
mentioned at the top of the show here
that I was a supporter of the Ukraine
and its resistance against the Russian
invasion, but you continually brought
up, you know, Zalinsky, not a Democrat,
you know, um Zalinsky, the corruption
that was starting to show its face.
Where was the money going? We didn't
even know what happened, for instance,
to Russians who were taken prisoners.
Uh, have we ever seen or heard a report
about what what Ukraine does with
Russian PS?
I haven't, and I've made a concerted
effort to look. I couldn't just be
looking in the wrong places. The point
is that democracy's got a democracy, you
know, that's just there's no other way
around it. And so when you're supporting
someone who is supposedly a um you know
fighting for democracy, he he was a duly
elected kind of dulyeleed as Ted will
give you the backstory on that. Uh but
he was
ostensibly a duly elected uh president
of Ukraine. But then he cancels
elections. He cancels regional
elections. And people here are, and this
is what drives me crazy, Ted, is people
here in the in in the um diaspora of the
of political talk make excuses for
anything. He says, "Well, he's having a
war." Well, you know, guess what, folks?
The United States had elections during a
[__] civil war.
You can have elections. They're not that
hard to hold. Uh regardless of the
circumstance. Yes, they'd be
extraordinary circumstances, but what a
message to the world to say, "Yeah, you
know, even though we're being invaded by
an overwhelming force, we still are
holding him off enough to have
elections." And that would have been an
extraordinary moment. Zalinsky chose not
to do that. He he I
>> Well, he was concerned about what's the
word? Losing.
>> Well, there I don't know that he would
have lost the early elections. Who
knows? I mean, that's the thing about
elections. You don't know. That's why
they hold them.
>> Remember, he only had he had very low
approval rating before the war began.
So,
>> did he?
>> Yeah, he he was he was in the toilet. I
mean, he was he I mean, he had he would
he would be he would have been jealous
of the numbers Trump has right now.
>> And he could have I mean, yeah, he
could. And you can always bring that
back. Don't forget um Oh, what was his U
Yeltson was was polling at 9% when he
ran for reelection in Russia. Uh
>> I'm surprised. I'm like, who are these
9%?
>> His family and the oligarchs he gave
stuff to
>> bartender. Um,
>> so to finish the thought, you have been
you've been on the cutting edge of this
story as you are so often on and you get
no credit for it. You have been pointing
this out for years and um some of us
began to listen to you and began to
look, oh yeah, Ted's right. This is this
is this is corrupt. It's undemocratic.
Uh we're backing the wrong horse or or
we shouldn't be backing any horse. We
should just be going, "Wow, look at
that. That stuff's happening." Hm.
And you know,
maybe that's what Trump means when he
says this wouldn't have happened under
his watch because
>> Well, I don't really want to read I
mean, I don't know. We can relitigate
the whole Ukraine war and I'm always
happy to do that because I feel like I I
you know, I was I I feel okay with my
position, right? I'm not running away
from it. And I don't run away from my
positions when I change them either. But
in this particular case, what I really
wanted to focus on is this is this
report from the New York Times, which is
like I'm shocked, shocked, shocked to
find corruption here. Yes. Um I mean
it's like they basically Ukraine has had
uh you know has been ranked something
like number 173 uh by Transparency
International's list of uh most
transparent countries and least corrupt
countries. I mean, it's it's long had a
long-standing corruption problem, even
by the standards of former Soviet
republics. Um, and even prezilinsky as
well, Zalinsky ran in part claiming that
there wouldn't be corruption. He did
have a pretty funny joke when he was
running. He was asked like, "Can anyone
be president of of Ukraine without
stealing?" I don't know. We should we
should try to find out. Well, apparently
we did find out. Apparently the answer
is still no. Um but according to the New
York Times which has been you know
running interference for Zilinski and
you know very for for three years plus
um you know they're saying that uh
Ukraine set up these oversight boards to
make sure that there's no corruption but
you know you basically Zilinsky stacked
those boards with his buddies left the
seats completely empty what Hunter Biden
wasn't available or stalled [laughter]
them from being set up at all and that
they even re that Zilinsky even rewrote
the company charters so that there would
be no oversight whatsoever. The point is
here's the issue, Scott. Even if we
think that Ukraine is a righteous cause
or any country is a righteous cause and
that we should interfere in that and I
don't believe in that. I I don't I just
don't we the US experiences with regime
change. I don't even but but like okay
shouldn't you as a as a as a caretaker
of American taxpayer funds how can you
fund a wildly corrupt country when you
know that all the money is not going to
go to the defense of that country it's
going to be stolen and and go to and go
to pay for villas in Lake Ko that's what
happened here any [__] could see it
coming because of Ukraine's current and
recent history of corruption I I mean,
on that basis alone, I would have said
like, "Well, we love you Ukrainians. You
guys are beautiful. Love you. You're all
blonde and everything. Can't help
because we don't trust you. We don't
think you'll I mean, look at all the
billions we poured into Afghanistan into
again a wildly corrupt government. Um,
and all the money, you know, the the
soldiers who wanted to fight the Taliban
didn't have m didn't have ammunition
because all the money was stolen." So, I
mean, you can't really help a corrupt
country is my point,
>> right? And the reason I brought up all
the other earlier stuff is that, you
know, it just set the table for
corruption. You know, when you're
supposed to be a a a democratic in, you
know, country with democratic
institutions that presumably have
safeguards and governors to prevent
corruption. That's basically what we we,
you know, what we do or what democracies
do. And when you get rid of democracy,
then you set the table. You're going
you're going to have corruption. It's
inevitable. It's going to happen. And
that's what's happened here. Um, you
know, and the the world is handing this
guy lottery, you know, big lotteryized
checks on foam core. You you're already
a winner. [laughter] It's a billion
dollars for this, a billion dollars for
that with no accountability. Well,
again, sticky fingers are going to um
are going to imp
>> Oh my god, I love I love I love Elliot's
comment. The irony of American foreign
policy. People who don't understand how
to govern Ohio or Michigan think they
know how to govern a country with a
totally different culture and history
across [laughter] the ocean.
Can't say it better, so I'm not going to
try. Um Philip Blair, u thank you for
this uh this that that an that 14minute
movie was called Innocence of Muslims.
It's an anti-Islamic film written and
produced by Nakula Basilei Nakula. Um so
that's that's that's the film that Arab
Spring thing that prov you know
provocative thing. Um
yeah um sneaker dad most people believed
Ukraine was a democracy and they were
wrong in a big way. Yeah. Um, you know,
and here's the thing, and this is a this
is an academic question, but you know,
if you're assessing, first of all, I'm
not sure that every democracy needs US
defense dollars, but like like, okay,
but let's just say that that's the the
metric somehow. Um, the the the you
know, Ukraine was like barely a
democracy before 2022, right? I mean,
like they overthrew their democratically
elected president in 2014.
>> And so here's a question. If you
overthrow
a, you know, a guy undemocratically as
part of a partly CIA, partly Nazif
funded coup, which is what happened,
then is this are his successors
legitimate? And I'm like,
is maybe
>> eventually
>> eventually I mean, yeah, it's it's hard
to say historically, right?
Um, okay. So, I think we can sort of
agree. So, if you had to go back, if we
had to go through this again and say
like, oh, like a a terrible um, you
know, a terrible country, let's say,
let's say China. Oh, here's a question
for you, Scott, and then we'll move on.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Let's say China attacks
Taiwan, which is definitely a democracy.
Um,
how do you feel? Should should we help?
>> How do I feel? Or what is going to
happen?
>> Well, should how do you feel? Do you
think we should help?
We are so immersed in that relationship
that um I don't know that we'd have any
choice. I have to believe that you know
uh through treaty through um uh uh
mutual defense packs through just the
fact that they buy a bunch of our our
our ships and guns and bullets uh we're
going to be we're go in there. Should we
go in? Is that the hill that you want to
flush 100,000 American lives down? boy.
Um
I I'd have to think I'd have to think
long and hard on that. And I've not It's
weird because it's not like this is a
new issue, Ted. It's not like
>> No, it's not. And I haven't had the
time.
>> And I And my father-in-law was a
Taiwanese independence um advocate. Um
and and so I mean I
I know the issue. Here's the thing. I
don't I think it's a simple issue for
the US.
>> The official stance of the United States
government is that Taiwan is not an
independent republic. The official
stance of the United States government
is that Taiwan is part of China. Uh
we've assured China of that since for
for since the Nixon sorry since the Ford
administration. So um sorry Carter
Carter right. So basically you know we
can't defend a non-country.
So like in legally as far as we're
concerned unless we recognize American
independence
I mean Taiw unless we recognize Taiwan
independence they have to declare
independence
>> then then then then it it's so my my
point is it's I don't even think then we
should go but it's I'm a
non-interventionist but
>> there's nothing to talk about until that
happens.
>> Right.
>> No, it's it's and you're absolutely
correct. It's not a sovereign country.
It's not recognized by the United
Nations. is not really recognized by the
United States government as a sovereign
country. I wish it were. It should be. I
mean, it's it's been
>> maybe they would have to declare
independence first for that to happen.
>> Of course. Um
>> they haven't had the balls to do that
yet. So,
>> well, Trump, if you remember, on the
campaign trail has had alluded to just
saying, let's just, you know, just pull
the trigger. And if anyone's going to
just pull the trigger, it's this guy.
And he hasn't done it. He's looked, I
mean, he's looked at the um the dynamics
and said, "Okay, this is no, we can't.
This is this is this is going to be get
way too messy. And so um so given what
you've just stated, I'm I'm
anti-intervention now, too. I mean, I I
tend to get seduced by, oh, this sounds
like a good idea until it's not.
[laughter]
>> Well, that's that's the American way. Um
>> but yeah, so so I think that's one thing
I respect about the Trump administration
so far, except for, you know, on some of
its foreign policy, which is that it's
against it doesn't like war. part sees
war is stupid, wasteful, expensive.
Um, you know, may and you can make the
case that maybe it's necessary, but I
would make the case that, you know, if
you look at many conflicts through a
historic lens that they were not
necessary and that America just got, you
know, hurt itself more by jumping in.
So, with Taiw, that's a great academic.
I'll have to give that some more
thought.
agents.
Those guys apparently they're fat and
stupid and they're um you know,
[laughter]
have you did you read those reports?
That's hilarious. We can send them.
>> Yeah, indeed. Indeed. Uh okay, so let's
see. Um okay, so sorry I I dropped the
feed a little bit. My apologies. That's
my fault. Uh, okay. So, let's see. We
have a we have an ad and I should go
ahead and read that ad.
>> Read it with Verve. I love that.
>> Always always with always with Verve.
Um,
okay.
Okay. Come on.
All right. Ready to level up your game?
Aim controllers is where custom meets
unbeatable value. And right now, it's
the best deal of the year. We start with
official Sony and Xbox box controllers.
Fully compatible with console and PC. No
functionality lost. Then you go wild
with custom features. Smart bumpers,
paddles, grips, stick height, custom
buttons, even design your own PS5 snap
panels. I don't uh And here's the part
no one else is doing. Lifetime warranty
on all Wow.
>> modified parts. That's right. Lifetime.
>> What other company does that? Exactly.
Normally a fully loaded setup could cost
you $400, but during our one price
promo, it's just $29 US or $182, no
matter how many features you add. Use
code rumble at checkout and lock it in.
This is your sign. Go to
aimcontrollers.com
and build the last controller you'll
ever need.
>> Oo, now that was Verve.
>> It al it it also it almost makes me want
to start gaming. Um, okay. So we should
talk about um we should obviously well
let's talk about this UK Novichuk
report. So back in 2018 um the British
authorities claimed that uh a British
national a 44 year old woman uh mother
of three um died from uh nerve nerve
agent called Novachot. claimed that this
was a um militaryra
nerve agent. And basically their theory
was that a pair of Russian uh FSB
operatives had been sent to the UK to
kill a Russian anti-Putin dissident. Uh
basically that the operation was called
off. So the derps threw it away. Um and
then uh basically uh somehow it came
into the into contact the perfume bottle
containing the agent that had been
dumped in a trash can uh somehow ended
up being exposed. This woman was exposed
to it.
>> Oh no, no, no. The story gets better,
Ted.
>> And she died.
>> Her hus partner
>> um gave it to her as a gift. [laughter]
>> Dumpster diving partner. Yeah. Well, he
claims he got it at a charity bin, which
I'm not sure this is a BBC report, which
I'm assuming is a thrift store or
something like that. So, yeah. So, he
bought her some used perfume. [laughter]
>> I love you, baby.
>> I love you. I love you so good. You love
me so much.
>> And she sprayed it on her wrist and
>> you smell so good. Wait, what's
happening? Wait, what's wrong, honey?
Honey.
Okay. So now, so look, that story has
more holes in it than, you know, more
holes in it than a Venezuela attack um,
you know, propaganda video. But now the
new report, the British are doubling,
tripling down on this. And now they're
saying, well, it's Putin who sent this
in to uh sent these FSB operatives to
kill someone who they didn't kill. And
so Putin should be and the Russians
should be held legally and morally and
ethically responsible for what happened
here. Um, I'm going to just say that I
don't know if I really want to call
[__] on it because I'm not sure it
quite rises to the level of being as
credible as [__] but it's pretty
it's pretty lame. I mean is I mean it
just seems now that like with the loss
of Ukraine the West is struggling to
find ways to remind everyone why Russia
is evil.
>> Well I mean how I mean from what I can
read and I can only read what is
available obviously and that is that
this this woman in the perfume was she
did apparently die from exposure to a
nerve agent. Um, initially they thought
um it was it was something else that uh
she was actually they actually called
her a drug addict and the BBC reported
her as a drug addict her being a drug
addict and died from an overdose.
Um,
now they're now you know the I'm I'm
assuming this is based on toxicology and
based on fact. God knows you know we've
never been lied to by government before.
Chad, [laughter]
>> especially not especially not about a
rival government who we don't who you
know our people don't like.
>> So what what makes you what makes you
think that this doesn't pass the smell
test?
>> Well, okay. So, first of all, we're
being told that there's ways to sort of
ID a nerve agent and say, you know,
okay, well, we know based on the
chemical composition of this thing, not
only that only a cert only a nation
state could have made it. Um, but on top
of that, we know which nation state it
came from. So, here's the thing. Um, you
know, I know I didn't graduate, but I
did do three years at Columbia School of
Engineering and applied scientist uh as
an app as an applied physics and nuclear
engineering major. And let me just say
that like that kind of chemical doesn't
have this isn't like you can identify
radioactive substances pretty well. Like
you can pretty much say where a certain
batch of plutonium came from or uranium,
but you can't really and not with a 100%
certainty, but with let's say 90%
certainty. Um, you can't do that with a
nerve agent. You can't there's just no
identifying markers. So, it's like
they're they're saying something that's
not true from a physics standpoint and
from a chemical composition standpoint.
So, just on that basis alone, I never
believed the story. Uh, and we don't I
mean, it's kind of like also where's the
proof that this was a nerve agent at
all? And nerve agents can come from
anywhere, right? I mean, hell, like they
could have originated in the UK. um you
know who it could have been some you
know industrial disposal where some
someone stole this from a factory uh or
and you know and dumped it and then
thought better of it dumped it into a
dumpster where it end you know where it
ended up at the tag sale right I mean I
don't know I just I just I you know is
it possible that this is ex this went
down exactly the way that the uh the
Brits say sure but you know it's there's
just not enough certainty there to say
we're going to I mean it feels like a
real stretch to be like Russian
President Vladimir Putin murdered this
woman.
>> Yeah. That's where the report gets it
comes off the rails. Um and their their
connection was that there was a
dissident a Russian dissident that lived
nearby.
That's where this could have come from.
Um and that seems fairly weak tea as
well. But you're right, Ted. the the the
the way the report meanders along and I
read a little p piece of it this
morning. It sort of goes duper dup maybe
these, you know, some dissident. This is
sort of the MMO for Russian agents is to
poison these guys. This is the poison
they used dah and Putin
and you're kind of sitting there reading
looking at this thing kind of going
wait what did Putin actually did do you
think Putin actually had like a card
table like a f foldable card table and
had a little box of these perfumes? He
was just sort of [laughter] everything
must go.
>> It's like
>> deadly perfume barely used [laughter]
is is makes ladies of girls smell the
way that they smell
>> like cabbage and potatoes. [laughter]
Who does not love?
>> Yeah. It's a Yeah.
>> Yeah. So you're I Ted, your smell your
your smell meter kind of
picking up on this. Yeah. To say to go
from it's it's going from
let's give it let's give it the best
spin. Some goofy agents were there.
They're going to try and douse this guy
and they were going to kill his daughter
as well apparent allegedly. Um and give
her some perfume which seems weird if
they wanted to kill him but let's I'm
don't know what they're into. Um, and
then it didn't work, so they throw it
out. I mean, this isn't this isn't stuff
that gets approved at the highest
levels, you know.
>> This isn't
>> right. That's that's that's a fair
point, too, right? I mean, so yeah, even
if this were I don't know. Let's let's
bra let's blame that American admiral.
Apparently, he's taking the fall for
everything these days. Um, let's move
on. Let's move on to him. Um, so
>> yes,
>> uh there's a lot to talk about uh with
this drone. this, sorry, the um not the
Yemen. I don't know why the thing says
Yemen. Um but with the uh boat attack in
uh
>> off the coast of Venezuela.
>> In Venezuela. Yeah. So, basically the
only I was talking to Jeral Thomas. Um
he interviewed me this morning about
this earlier before our show. Um and he
brings up a he brought up a really good
point which is you know why do we only
care? This is a double tap strike. So
double tap strike um as at least in
recent history originated with something
that um the Bush and Obama
administrations used to do all the time
in places like Pakistan and they
probably you know I'm sure it still
happens. Basically, you bomb a target,
like usually a car for example, and then
passers by, good Samaritans, first
responders, ambulance workers, doctors,
nurses, they come to assist, and then
haha, aren't we funny? Then we drop
another bomb in the same spot and kill
all of them. That's called a double top
strike. Um, you know, to basically
everyone kind of agrees that's gross.
Um, you know, and and yet, you know, we
do it all the time. So that's what
happened here. It's a double tap strike.
Um the this the the
changing narratives of the of the Trump
administration definitely raised my
hackles. I mean there's lots of times
when you can have a changing story or a
changing narrative. That's still totally
true because you're trying to figure out
what happened or you're looking at it
from a different point of view. But in
this particular case, this re this event
was recorded right on video and it was
recorded internally and there are
detailed logs. So we blew up this boat.
It was 40 feet long. There were two
survivors presumably injured on the high
seas clinging to a piece of wood in the
middle of the of of the um of the
Caribbean. Um the we we observed them
for 41 minutes and then we dropped
another bomb on them and killed them. I
mean I guess to me that the we what we
should have claimed was that it was a
coup grass to put them out of put people
who were going to die for sure out of
their misery. Instead you have this
story that first of all a that didn't
happen. Well okay b it did happen. Then
it's like okay well it was heath. Well
no it wasn't heath. It was this
admirable oh where was heath? He gave
the order. No, Heath was at the bar or
wherever.
>> He's busy. Yeah. He said literally, "I
was busy. There's a lot to do at the
Department of War. [laughter]
>> He was out waring." So, so this So then,
so all these narratives keep changing
and then it's like, "But it was the
admiral, but we think he was totally
right." And now there's a congressman
said, "Oh, actually there was a third
and a fourth strike." And I don't know
if he was joking and being sarcastic or
if he's being or if he's being real. The
point is, um, the certain members of
Congress were briefed. They saw the
video. Democrats came out of it saying
that they'd never seen anything quite
like it, even though they'd seen video
of other uh, aerial attacks by the
United States that killed people. And
the Republicans came out of it saying
all AOKs, just like normal. Um, so
there's a lot going on here. um these I
mean and the New York Times finally gets
around today to questioning well are any
of the 87 deaths legal and is it maybe
the problem here you know obviously we
all kind of agree it's not sporting to
to to blow up people who are clinging to
a piece of wood the the administration
actually argued Scott that like they
were calling for backup that they were
like on narot terrorist 911 like calling
Harvey Keitel from Pulp Fiction to come
save their ass, you know, come and come
and help. Well, they were they could
have gotten help. And I'm like, okay,
well, at that point, they could have
gotten into a UFO and and started an
alien invasion of the Earth. I mean,
anything could happen, but I mean, come
on. They're in the middle of the ocean.
There's no evidence for anything. They
were trying to write their boat.
>> Okay, the boat was blown to smitherines,
but Scott, it was a 40 foot boat in the
middle of the ocean. Even if it hadn't
been blown up, like you know, if you and
I are in the middle of the ocean, let's
say we're both 25 and in tip-top
physical condition, we can't turn over a
40 foot boat.
>> I mean, I don't 10 guys can't turn over
a 40 foot boat.
>> Not in the water. No. No.
>> Um, it's it has made people very
uncomfortable. However, it's polling.
It's one of the few areas where Trump is
actually polling pretty well. people
aren't as a gasast at this as they
should be because they should be. Um
I was there's a conservative site here
in Alabama called 1819 and the editor of
it who was who is a remarkable story.
Quick story. U a former he had been in
prison and cleaned up his life, got got
his crap together and is now the uh uh
you know the executive who runs 1819,
but he came out with a with a tweet or
an X or whatever it's called today and
said that you know due process I mean
yeah should due process but I mean not
everyone deserves due process. I'm
thinking this is a guy who went through
a system that gave him due process. It
seemed like
>> and yes, actually that's the whole point
of due process is that everybody does
deserve due process.
>> Yes. And so given that there's no due
process, that there's no evidence, they
they've get this administration has
given us no no hard evidence that that
these boats are indeed carrying drugs.
Uh the New York Times did do a story on
one of the ship one of the boats that
had been blown up. And the guy he was a
fisherman on, you know, in a crappy
little town in Venezuela. Mhm.
>> So to make some extra money, yeah, once
in a while he'd move drugs. I'm not
defending his moving his being a drug
mule, but you know, it was once in a
while. They had no idea if that ship
they blew up of his at that time had
drugs, had illicit drugs destined for
American streets on it or not. And by
the way, Ted, I mean, the other thing
about this whole war on drugs and
getting rid of these guys is that a it's
never effective. It never it never slows
things down very much. I mean, we had
prohibition. We can look at that as the
number one model of failure of the
government trying to prohibit people
from taking illicit illicit uh
substances. And two, I mean, isn't the
problem really Americans taking
these drugs? I mean, that's the fact
that there's a market for that in
America. They're not shipping.
>> But there's not even a market. They're
not shipping these drugs to America.
These drugs, um, you know, the US is
suffering from a major drug problem. Uh,
you know, the opioid crisis though is
not the this they make cocaine. They
send it to Africa. You know, they they
send it to Trinidad. These boats are not
coming to the United States and they're
if they were, they'd be bringing
cocaine, not fentanyl. Um, I mean, the
point is the administration is lying
about this. Uh, the president claims
that every boat he blows up saves 25,000
lives.
>> It's not saving any life. None. And if
it were, it'd be saving African lives,
not American lives.
>> And yeah, and you know how much this
Trump cares about African lives,
especially Somali.
>> Yeah, he loves them.
>> Oh my god. Like there his own children.
Um,
>> by the way,
says the second strike by admission was
done blindly in the fog of war, amateur
hour. Yeah. I mean, that's that's
literally what what Hegat said. It was
the fog of war. We couldn't see the
target. Okay. But by definition, you're
not allowed under the American rules of
engagement
>> to shoot something you can't see. So get
your story straight.
>> They they don't have it. The story is
that Hexus was there and was trying to
impress himself or was, you know, he was
on his third martini, his his breakfast
martini, and they saw this and he got,
you know, excited and decided to wipe
these guys out. It's egregious. It's a
war crime. It's it's it's plain and
simple. I'm sorry. You can, you know.
>> Well, it's murder.
>> It's Well, yeah.
>> Oh, I love fuso. Fuso. Thanks for the
dollar. If we were really serious about
killing drug smugglers, we'd be bombing
the CIA. Fair point. [laughter] Um,
>> we know at least we'd know where to find
them.
>> Very good. Very good. No, if we really
wanted to, I mean, we would be bombing
Chinese ships headed for Mexico and we'd
be d bombing Mexico. I mean, I don't But
we're not.
>> Well, that's true. Um, and that's
something that producer Robbie has
pointed out um, in the past. Um, hey, so
we should talk about Trump's approval
ratings in the minutes we have left. By
the way, if you're joining us late,
thanks for joining us. Please like,
follow, and share the show. We're here
Monday through Friday uh, here on
Drogram uh, at 9:00 a.m. Eastern time.
John Kuryaku is out today. He's
attending a relative's funeral. He'll be
back on Monday. Um, okay. So, um, you
know, what's your what you would you
want to handicap Hegat's career odds?
Uh, is he still, you know, in this
administration by Monday?
>> Have there ever been I I'm trying to
think in the first Trump, you know,
version 1.0, was there ever an official
who got in tr in trouble with the media
and the general public who that then
Trump jettisoned?
I'm trying to think. I mean, there was
um Secretary of Defense. I mean, I know
secretary I mean, the attorney general
uh former uh former senator from Alabama
um Jeff Sessions, but he just because he
refused to prosecute things in a way
that Trump liked. So, he fired him. But
I don't remember anyone like getting
into this kind of trouble and then Trump
saying, you know, he always doubles down
on these guys.
>> You know what, Scott? I got to I got to
hand that to you. Um I was thinking that
there was a better than 5050 chance of
Hex Seth being removed, but you're
right. you what you just said makes it
lower than 5050 because Trump doesn't do
that. He doesn't he doesn't cut people
loose just because the the uh you know
there's pressure from Congress or the
media or from the voters. Uh he he only
cuts them loose if they personally are
disloyal or offend him personally.
>> Yeah.
>> Um no I I I think I like that. Okay. So
um we need to talk um about Trump's
polls. Uh yesterday on the DMZ America
podcast, you and I uh were joined by a
pundit. We we were handicapping the
midterm elections. Uh new polls just
came out after that. Currently 55%
disapprove of Trump's u job performance.
He's down to 42%. These are Bidenike
levels. Not good. Um his biggest loss is
among the place where he had had his
biggest wins that brought him to power
among independents. 31% approve of still
approve of Trump independence, but
that's down from 41% just five months
ago, Scott. Um, that's a pretty
significant fall, isn't it?
>> It's the economy. I mean I mean I I hate
to drag this old trope out, but it
really is the economy, stupid. The
economy is performing badly. And as we
touched on at the top of this of this
hour, um,
you can't Trump can't just dismiss it
and say everything's fine. I'm not
hurting. I can afford things. Um, you
know, you can't dismiss the American
consumer's pain and they are going
through some significant pain right now.
You go to the grocery store, I go to the
grocery store and we buy stuff and you
know, you've just dumped 130 bucks on
one bag of groceries and it's not like
we're buying filet minan and anything.
It's like, you know,
>> potato helper or whatever the hell we
eat. I don't even know. Um but
[laughter]
um the fact that you can't you have to
address inflation first of all you have
to admit it's happening and you have to
address it in a serious way and this
administration is in no way shape or
form is doing that and they and you
can't fix it quickly. You know Trump
tried to drop the the tariffs the Trump
taxes on uh food items and it hasn't
really had an appreciable effect. Have
you gone Ted? You're you're you're
French. I'm French. We like beef very
much.
>> We And um have you gone have you have
you looked at the price of beef lately?
>> It is crazy. Uh it Yes. It reminds me a
lot of uh this old Mike Peters cartoon
from the inflationary period in the
1970s
uh and uh a person goes into a butcher
shop and uh the and the butcher is like
we would when you put like to put that
steak on layaway. We also [laughter]
>> Yeah. You guess take a guess. I'm not
sure if you've looked um stew me stew
beef you know for stew for chili you
know this is not the best cuts you know
guess how much
>> 10 bucks a 10 10 bucks a pound for the
shitty stuff
>> yeah yeah the good stuff is like 20 25
>> well okay so getting back to your
question the American people are seeing
this they're not seeing gas prices budge
I mean I think 250 seems not outrageous
price for gasoline in the 21st century
America but he promised that those
prices would come down They haven't.
>> No.
>> Um, and they're looking at this guy
who's spending an awful lot of time
blowing up boats and, you know,
threatening and trying to garner peace
between uh Djibouti and Somalia or
whatever the hell he's on today. Um,
that that's hurting him. I think that is
absolutely the gist and the crux of what
his where the problem is.
>> East. Yeah. The like literally as we I'm
glad you brought this up, Scott. So, I
mean, lest anyone think you're joking,
Trump literally just announced his
latest agreement between Congo and
Rwanda. So, I guess
>> Democratic dem the Democratic Republic
of Congo. Two different Congo, by the
way.
>> Yeah, there are two different Congo. So,
but this is the big one. Uh, formerly
Zire, right? Um, and you know, uh, I
can't help but note the fact that this
is of great interest because Eastern
Congo be full of blood diamonds, right?
So, uh, lot and lots of other rare earth
minerals and blah blah.
>> Not gold leaf because that would be then
we'd be at war with them.
>> Well, that's all the all the gold leaf
has now been used. It's all on the wall
at the at the Oval Office.
>> Oh my god, Ted. It looks like And so it
looks like a French house. It is a It is
egregious. And now they have the sign
outside that in gold calligraphy that
says the Oval Office. Have you seen
this?
>> No, I have not seen that. And they have
that the breezeway that goes from the
residency to the Oval Office that now is
the walk of the presidential walk of
fame.
>> Oh, is that with with the one with the
with the Biden picture of the
>> the auto
we never talked about this because Ted
and I are both cartoonists aesthetics
matter to us but the official portrait
of Trump now the
>> Yeah. Well, he said he I I read that he
like actually practic, you know, he
actually is has silly expressions in
private and he's very smiley, but he he
on purpose when he's public, he said
that he read a biography of Churchill
and that Churchill always scowlled and
so he feels that like to look like a
tough guy, he always has to be, you
know, like look like scowlly and mean.
>> I'm just laughing at the idea of Donald
Trump reading a book. Um,
sorry.
>> Yeah. [laughter] Well, maybe he he read
about someone writing a book or
something. [laughter]
I don't know. Um, yeah. I mean, he's
going to try to buy us off. You I know
you're going to love this. Next time I
see you, we'll talk about this, but
Trump wants to give everyone 2,000 bucks
each. So, he wants to I know you are
hugely in favor of that sort of thing.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> As a fiscal conservative.
>> Anyway, guys, thanks for tuning in and
thanks for hanging out this week. Uh,
you've been watching the program with
Ted Roll and John Kuryaku with editorial
cartoonist for the Chicago Tribune,
Scott Stantis and my good friends
sitting in. Uh, please stay tuned. The
TMI show with me and Manila Chan is
coming right up. Uh, Ruth Rumble, you
just sit tight. It'll just go automatic
on YouTube. You've got to actually make
an effort and go look. Uh, we will be
back Monday at 9:00 am here. John
Kuryako will be back. And so, we're
looking forward to all that. Scott, nice
to see you. Have a great weekend.
>> It was great.
>> Bye.
[music]